# Mikiko Bazeley

SF Bay Area, CA | mmbazel@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/mikikobazeley | github.com/MMBazel | medium.com/@mmbazel

#### SUMMARY

Software Engineer with 5+ years shipping ML models & data-driven solutions for high-growth companies in a variety of industries (solar, construction, recruitment-tech, & health-tech). Focused on full-cycle product engineering, including data engineering, ML model development, deployment, serving, monitoring & evaluation. Speaker, consultant, & mentor for initiatives & organizations focused on increasing representation in data science & machine learning.

## **EXPERIENCE**

INTUIT - San Francisco, CA

Senior SWE, ML Platform & Infrastructure

Nov 2021 - Present May 2021 - Nov 2021

SWE, et al. (Mailchimp)

Summary: SWE focused on developing ML Platform & operations to efficiently scale model pipeline training & deployment, integration, testing & monitoring for the Data Science team using GCP, etc.

- Shipped improvements to DS project templating tools (cookiecutter, etc.), including bug fixes & patches
- Provided initial analysis of project health of ML projects in production
- Lead change management of major upstream templating updates to 50+ downstream repos, as well as managing merge conflicts, performing code reviews, & developing initial repo health checklist
- Helped develop workshops & internal training on software engineering best practices for Data Science team, including testing
- Assisted with interviews for junior & senior software engineers

#### SIDEWALK.AI - San Francisco, CA

# Machine Learning Engineer

May 2019 - Jan 2021

Summary: First MLE at early-stage start-up focused on building Al-first enablement tools for residential real-state.

- Developed ML roadmap, research & implemented proof-of-concept models from papers (in listing recommendations, user profile clustering) utilizing Python (Scikit-learn, Surprise, Dask, GeoPandas), AWS RDS, Jupyter
- Developed early iteration of ETL pipelines using Python (including SQLAlchemy, paramiko, Dask) with logging, data cataloguing, & job status tracking for processing 1000+ text files (up to 8MB in size)
- Designed data models & schema, created DDL & DML scripts for Postgres (then Amazon RDS)
- Researched, documented, & acquired external datasets through scraping (Python Requests, BeautifulSoup, Scrapy) as well as through APIs (Quandl, Kaggle, etc)

## TELADOC - Mountain View, CA

#### Data Scientist II, Growth Marketing

Oct 2019 - Nov 2020

**Summary:** Collaborate closely with senior management to increase enrollment, activation & retention for members living with chronic & behavioral conditions (Diabetes, Hypertension, Pre-Diabetes, Weight Management).

- Provided experimentation support: Designed, set-up, & analyzed experiment results, including A/B tests (Python, Seaborn, SciPy, statsmodels, Metabase, SQLAlchemy)
- Lead projects in developing, documenting, scripting, & visualizing key metrics & analyses around marketing & growth
- Developed machine learning models (classification, regression, time series) & pipelines using Python (Pandas, Scikit-learn, Prophet, statsmodels), Redshift, S3. Leverage Metabase, Tableau & TabPy to engage stakeholders with analyses & machine learning model outputs around forecasting & prediction

WALKME - San Francisco, CA

**Summary:** Responsible for leading & executing advanced analytics & data science initiatives for the revenue operations organization. Worked with key stakeholders to scope, develop, & present ML models.

- Developed sales & marketing pipeline demand model to set sales targets, evaluate pipeline funding options, & monitor key metrics (lead generation, lead coverage, opportunity conversion). Leveraged Python, Google sheets, Redshift, Tableau. Made strategic recommendations using model results to prevent potential risk of \$4M+ global revenue target miss.
- Developed pipeline allocation model & pipeline (with Python, Numpy) allocating lead generation targets from Demand Model to teams & individuals based on quota, start date & quota ramp. Model output ingested into external BI tool & CRM (Clari, Tableau) for real-time tracking of sales & actionable insight into opportunity velocity, leading to improvements in sales forecasting.
- Created propensity-to-purchase model using Salesforce data (opportunity, lead, & call records) as well as Python
  (simple-salesforce, NLTK, Spacy, Scikit-learn). Using features created around lead job titles, prospect account pain points, &
  historic demo call data, developed random forest model to predict propensity-to-first-purchase of account. Provided model
  interpretability using pdpbox, SHAP, & Scikit-learn.

#### AUTODESK - San Francisco, CA

## Data Scientist, Customer Adoption

Jul 2017 - Aug 2018

**Summary**: Sole data science asset focused on understanding & driving user adoption of core products of construction software portfolio.

• Created customer scoring model in R utilizing account demographics, subscription & product usage data to flag customers struggling with product adoption. Model outputs scheduled for upload to Salesforce & Domo via scheduler, RForcecom, etc. with status reports automatically emailed to account owners via mailR.

VARIOUS COMPANIES - SF Bay Area, CA

Various Roles, Business Operations

Dec 2013 - Jul 2017

Summary: Held various roles for a number of early- to mid-stage start-ups in bizops growth, and customer service. Companies: Sunrun (Analyst), Digimarc Guardian (BizOps Associate), RecruitLoop (Growth Hacker), eSalon (Manager)

## ADDITIONAL - TEACHING, MEDIA, HONORS, COMPETITIONS

AMAZON SPONSORED: GHC2020 WOMEN IN BOOTCAMP- AnitaB.Org

Scholarship: https://bit.ly/20LNgju

Jun 2020

(NOT IRL) PRIDE SUMMIT- Lesbians Who Tech

Selected Speaker: https://bit.lv/3fgJY0d

Jun 2020

**Description**: Led 30min Ted talk for over 100+ attendees on data visualization topic, "Visualizing History with Python:

Reproducing WEB Du Bois' Paris Exposition Exhibit, 35 years".

CAREER PANEL: WOMEN IN DATA SCIENCE - General Assembly

Invited Speaker: https://bit.ly/2BOZL86

Apr 2020

Description: Two-hour panel that featured "women who are successfully navigating the tech industry and developing

exceptional work while motivating change."

Competition Standings: Selected Competitor & Team Finals (MIT Covid Datathon), Top 8% [of 800 Teams] (WiDs GOSSIS 2020 Kaggle Competition)

Teaching: Data Science Mentor (Data Science Dream Job), Data Science & Analytics Mentor (Springboard)

Additional Speaking Appearance include: Artist of Data Science Podcast, Ken Jee's Nearest Neighbors, Career Karma, etc. Can be found here: <a href="https://github.com/MMBazel#-also-the-medias-">https://github.com/MMBazel#-also-the-medias-</a>

#### **EDUCATION**

## **SKILLS**

Languages: Python [PyTest, Great Expectations, scikit-learn, pandas, numpy, genism, spacy, OpenCV], SQL [Postgres, MySQL, Oracle], C++, Solidity, Rust

Applications: Docker, Kubernetes, Airflow, GCP [BigQuery, AI Platform, Dataflow], Streamlit, Flask, Databricks/PySpark,

FastAPI, Jenkins, Github Actions

Certificates: Full Stack Deep Learning, Deep Learning Specialization (*Coursera – deeplearning.ai*), Supply Chain Management (*Micromasters – MITx*), Database Programming: MySQL (*CCSF*), Data Science Bootcamp (*Springboard*), Machine Learning Engineering (*Springboard*)